Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我的名字是马可。
My name is Katherine and as you've noticed on our website, we have a number of lessons
我的名字是凯瑟琳，正如你在我们网站上看到的，我们有很多课程。
about giving a presentation in English.
关于用英语做演示。
So this is one of those lessons.
所以这是那种课程之一。
Today we're talking about avoiding questions.
今天我们来聊聊如何回避问题。
That's right.
没错。
Today in part five of our presentation series, we're going to try and handle some questions
今天是我们演讲系列的第五部分，我们将尝试处理一些问题。
or avoid questions as Katherine said.
或者像凯瑟琳说的那样，回避问题。
So why don't we jump into the dialogue.
那我们直接开始对话吧。
Let's see what Mr. Ford is talking about now and we'll be back in a bit.
让我们看看福特先生现在在说什么，我们一会儿就回来。
Now as we've already discussed, there's a huge untapped market out there, both in Asia,
正如我们之前讨论过的，亚洲市场潜力巨大，尚未被充分开发。
in other developing markets and in the more mature markets for us to push into.
在其他新兴市场以及更成熟的市场，我们都可以进一步拓展。
Now of course this represents an enormous challenge with enormous rewards for the winners.
当然，这对赢家来说既是巨大的挑战，也伴随着丰厚的回报。
But for any new product, we need a great marketing message and marketing campaign.
但对于任何新产品，我们都需要一个出色的营销信息和营销活动。
It needs to be directed and focused at our target consumer and needs to be pitched at
它需要针对我们的目标消费者进行定向和聚焦，并且需要以合适的定位来推广。
exactly the right level.
恰到好处的程度。
The question we must first address is of course, who is our target consumer and secondly, what
我们首先要解决的问题当然是：谁是我们的目标消费者？其次，是什么？
do they expect from the next generation alpha laptop?
他们对下一代 Alpha 笔记本电脑有什么期望？
Let's first of all tackle the first question.
首先，我们来解决第一个问题。
Our target consumer for the X420 is the middle class white collar worker with an above average
我们X420的目标消费者是收入高于平均水平的中产阶级白领。
income.
收入。
However, as we mentioned before, the total number of computer owners is expanding rapidly
然而，正如我们之前提到的，电脑拥有者的总数正在迅速增长。
and we need to broaden our audience for this product.
我们需要为这款产品扩大受众范围。
For example, the X420 is also ideally suited to the younger student sector who might use
例如，X420也非常适合年轻学生群体，他们可能会用笔记本电脑来学习和玩游戏。
laptops both for studying and gaming.
笔记本电脑既用于学习也用于游戏。
There's no doubt that...
毫无疑问...
Mr. Ford, if I could just interrupt a moment.
福特先生，请允许我打断一下。
You say that the computer is suitable for students, but you don't think the price of
您说这款电脑适合学生，但您不觉得X420的价格对大多数学生来说太高了吗？
the X420 is just too much for most students?
X420的价格对大多数学生来说太高了？
Well that's a fair point.
嗯，这个问题提得好。
If you don't mind, I'd like to tackle your question a little bit later in the Q&A section.
如果您不介意，我想在稍后的问答环节再回答您的问题。
Is that okay?
可以吗？
Yes, sure.
好的，当然可以。
Okay, so as I was saying, we have an exciting campaign planned for the X420.
好的，正如我刚才所说，我们为X420策划了一场激动人心的宣传活动。
Firstly we'll have a nationwide television campaign as well as advertising on radio and
首先，我们会在全国范围内进行电视广告宣传，同时也会在广播和许多电脑杂志上投放广告。
also in many computer publications.
以及许多电脑出版物上。
We also intend to...
我们还打算...
I'm sorry to stop you Mr. Ford, but do you really think that a television campaign is
抱歉打断您，福特先生，但您真的认为电视广告宣传划算吗？
cost effective?
成本效益高吗？
I mean, how much does that go into cost?
我是说，这会对成本产生多大影响？
Well I don't have the figures to hand, but I'd be happy to discuss those figures with
嗯，我手头没有具体数据，但很乐意在演示结束后和你讨论这些数字。
you after the presentation.
你可以在演示结束后和我讨论。
Okay let me just go on to talk a little more about the exciting campaign we have in store.
好的，让我继续谈谈我们准备推出的精彩活动。
All right we're back and now we can get started with Language Takeaway.
好了，我们回来了，现在可以开始“语言精华”环节了。
Language Takeaway.
语言精华。
Okay so Marco, a lot of the conversation today was about markets and a target consumer.
好的，Marco，今天的对话很多是关于市场和目标消费者的。
So perhaps we should start talking a little bit about who Mr. Ford thinks this company's
所以也许我们应该先谈谈福特先生认为这家公司的
consumers are.
消费者是谁。
That's right.
没错。
He mentioned that the Alpha laptop could also be aimed at the middle class.
他提到Alpha笔记本电脑也可以瞄准中产阶级。
We have different classes in society, especially in America, where we talk about people who
社会中有不同的阶层，尤其是在美国，我们谈论那些
are low income, they don't make very much money, or people who make a lot of money,
低收入的人，他们赚得不多，或者那些赚很多钱的人，
they're rich, they're on top.
他们很富有，处于顶层。
That's the high class.
那是高阶层。
Yeah, high class.
是的，高阶层。
But in the middle, we have the middle class.
但在中间，我们有中产阶级。
And this is just average people.
这只是普通人。
They make money, they have a car.
他们赚钱，有车。
They're not rich, but they're not poor.
他们不富裕，但也不贫穷。
Okay so they're in the middle.
好的，所以他们处于中间位置。
So this is the middle class.
所以这就是中产阶级。
The computer is aimed at the middle class market, but he said that it's middle class
这款电脑瞄准的是中产阶级市场，但他说这是中产阶级
white collar worker.
白领工人。
Okay so I know this phrase exists in many other languages, but a white collar worker
好的，我知道这个短语在很多其他语言中也存在，但“白领工人”
in English means, refers to the color of the shirt that you wear.
在英语中指的是你衬衫的颜色。
So white collar workers usually work in offices.
所以白领工人通常在办公室工作。
So because they're usually wearing suits.
因为他们通常穿西装。
That's right, they have to wear nice clothes like suits and button down shirts.
没错，他们得穿好衣服，比如西装和纽扣衬衫。
But we sometimes also talk about blue collar workers.
但我们有时也会谈到蓝领工人。
Who are these guys?
这些人是谁？
Blue collar workers are usually people that are in trades, like for example a mechanic
蓝领工人通常是从事行业的人，比如机械师
or a plumber, because usually you see them wearing those blue shirts.
或水管工，因为你通常看到他们穿那些蓝色衬衫。
Yeah, uniforms.
是的，制服。
They're usually people who work with their hands or who are not likely to work in a big
他们通常是动手工作的人，或者不太可能在大型
office.
办公室工作。
So usually maybe these people are not middle class, maybe they are lower class.
所以通常这些人可能不是中产阶级，可能是下层阶级。
They can be both.
他们两者都可能。
In America right now I think you can make quite a bit of money if you're a plumber or
在美国现在，我觉得如果你是个水管工或
construction worker.
建筑工人，你可以赚不少钱。
That's right.
没错。
But he also mentioned middle class white collar worker with an above average income.
但他还提到了中产阶级白领，收入高于平均水平。
Okay so an income is the amount of money that a person earns, usually in a year.
好的，所以收入是指一个人赚的钱的数额，通常是一年内的。
So we say $30,000 a year.
所以我们说一年三万美元。
That's your annual income.
那是你的年收入。
That's right.
没错。
So when we talk about something that's average, that means it's normal.
所以当我们谈论某件事是平均水平时，意思是它是正常的。
But in this case we're not talking about something that's average.
但在这个案例中，我们不是在谈论平均水平的东西。
What are we talking about?
我们在谈论什么？
It's above average.
是高于平均水平。
Above average.
高于平均水平。
So if the average income of a person in America is $36,000 a year, an above average income
所以如果美国人的平均年收入是三万六千美元，那么高于平均水平的收入
is $70,000 a year or $65,000 a year.
就是一年七万美元或六万五千美元。
But for the middle class maybe that's different.
但对于中产阶级来说，可能有所不同。
So in the middle class an average annual income is $70,000.
所以中产阶级的平均年收入是七万美元。
An above average income in the middle class is $120,000 a year.
中产阶级中高于平均水平的收入是一年十二万美元。
So the phrase there above average, you're just referring to something that's more than
所以“高于平均水平”这个短语，你只是指比
the normal.
正常水平更多的东西。
That's right.
没错。
So in this case more than the normal income for a middle class worker.
所以在这个案例中，比中产阶级工人的正常收入更多。
You can also say below average.
你也可以说“低于平均水平”。
So a below average income is lower than most people earn.
所以低于平均水平的收入比大多数人赚的少。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
And well continuing on talking about markets and the demographics, who were selling the
嗯，继续谈论市场和人口统计，我们是在把
computer to, we also talked about our target consumer.
电脑卖给谁，我们还谈到了我们的目标消费者。
This is something that you often hear in meetings at work or in marketing departments.
这是你在工作会议或市场部门经常听到的。
A target is something you aim for.
目标是你瞄准的东西。
It's something you want to hit or achieve.
是你想要击中或实现的东西。
And so a target consumer is the buyer, is a customer that you aim to have.
所以目标消费者就是买家，是你希望拥有的顾客。
Okay.
好的。
So maybe you have some customers that they're students and you have some customers that
所以也许你有一些顾客是学生，还有一些顾客
they're very old, but your target consumer are the people that you really want to reach
年纪很大，但你的目标消费者是你真正想要接触
out to.
的人。
In this case, the middle class white collar worker.
在这个案例中，就是中产阶级白领。
That's right.
没错。
So in the case of our dialogue, our target consumer is a middle class white collar worker,
所以在我们的对话中，我们的目标消费者是中产阶级白领，
for example.
举个例子。
Okay.
好的。
So a lot of marketing stuff here talking about the computer and what Mr. Ford was saying.
所以这里有很多市场营销的内容，谈论电脑和福特先生说的话。
Let's take a pause.
让我们暂停一下。
Let's listen to the dialogue again and we'll be back with some phrases on how to defer
让我们再听一遍对话，稍后我们会回来讲一些关于如何推迟
questions.
问题的短语。
Now as we've already discussed, there's a huge untapped market out there, both in Asia
现在，正如我们已经讨论过的，有一个巨大的未开发市场，无论是在亚洲
and other developing markets and in the more mature markets for us to push into.
和其他发展中市场，还是在更成熟的市场，我们都可以打入。
Now of course this represents an enormous challenge with enormous rewards for the winners.
当然，这代表着巨大的挑战，对赢家来说也有巨大的回报。
But for any new product, we need a great marketing message and marketing campaign.
但对于任何新产品，我们需要一个出色的营销信息和营销活动。
It needs to be directed and focused at our target consumer and needs to be pitched at
它需要针对我们的目标消费者，并且需要以
exactly the right level.
恰到好处的水平进行推销。
The question we must first address is of course, who is our target consumer?
我们必须首先解决的问题当然是，我们的目标消费者是谁？
And secondly, what do they expect from the next generation alpha laptop?
其次，他们对下一代阿尔法笔记本电脑有什么期望？
Let's first of all tackle the first question.
让我们先处理第一个问题。
Our target consumer for the X420 is the middle class white collar worker with an above average
我们X420的目标消费者是收入高于平均水平的
income.
中产阶级白领。
However, as we mentioned before, the total number of computer owners is expanding rapidly
然而，正如我们之前提到的，电脑拥有者的总数正在迅速扩大，
and we need to broaden our audience for this product.
我们需要为这个产品拓宽受众。
For example, the X420 is also ideally suited to the younger student sector who might use
例如，X420也非常适合年轻学生群体，他们可能
laptops both for studying and gaming.
用笔记本电脑学习和玩游戏。
There's no doubt that...
毫无疑问...
Mr. Ford, if I could just interrupt a moment.
福特先生，如果我能打断一下。
You say that the computer is suitable for students, but you don't think the price of
你说这款电脑适合学生，但你不觉得X420的价格
the X420 is just too much for most students?
对大多数学生来说太贵了吗？
Well that's a fair point.
嗯，这是个合理的观点。
If you don't mind, I'd like to tackle your question a little bit later in the Q&A section.
如果你不介意，我想在问答环节稍后处理你的问题。
Is that okay?
可以吗？
Yes, sure.
好的，当然。
Okay, so as I was saying, we have an exciting campaign planned for the X420.
好的，正如我所说，我们为X420计划了一个激动人心的活动。
Firstly we'll have a nationwide television campaign as well as advertising on radio and
首先，我们将有一个全国性的电视广告活动，以及在广播和
also in many computer publications.
许多电脑出版物上的广告。
We also intend to...
我们还打算...
I'm sorry to stop you Mr. Ford, but do you really think that a television campaign is
抱歉打断你，福特先生，但你真的认为电视广告活动
cost effective?
是划算的吗？
I mean, how much does that go into cost?
我的意思是，成本是多少？
Well I don't have the figures to hand, but I'd be happy to discuss those figures with
嗯，我手头没有具体数字，但我很乐意在演示结束后
you after the presentation.
和你讨论这些数字。
Okay, let me just go on to talk a little more about the exciting campaign we have in store.
好的，让我继续谈谈我们准备的这个激动人心的活动。
Alright we're back, so now let's take a look at those phrases that we mentioned on Fluency
好了，我们回来了，现在让我们看看那些我们在流利度
Builder.
构建部分提到的短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
So Marco, there was a phrase that I heard twice in today's dialogue that I think we
所以马可，我在今天的对话中听到了一个短语两次，我想我们
should talk about.
应该讨论的。
The verb is to tackle, so we heard to tackle a question.
这个动词是 tackle，所以我们听到了“处理一个问题”。
Right, so when Mr. Ford says, I'll tackle that question a little bit later on, he's
对，所以当福特先生说“我稍后会处理那个问题”时，他是在
talking about I'll answer the question or I'll talk about that question later on.
说“我会回答那个问题”或“我稍后会讨论那个问题”。
Right, but in this word to tackle, there's something kind of physical about it because
对，但这个词“tackle”带有一些身体上的意味，因为
in football we say that when someone tries to hit the ball from someone else, it's a
在足球中，我们说当有人试图从别人脚下抢球时，那是
slide tackle.
一个滑铲。
And so to tackle a question means to really jump into it and try and solve it and it's
所以“处理一个问题”意味着真正投入进去，尝试解决它，而且
you know maybe not an easy question.
你知道，这可能不是一个简单的问题。
So I'm going to tackle that later.
所以我稍后会处理那个。
I'm going to tackle a challenge.
我要应对一个挑战。
It's more than just to solve a problem or to answer a question.
这不仅仅是解决问题或回答问题。
So maybe you can also tackle a project, a difficult project.
所以你也可以处理一个项目，一个困难的项目。
That's right, so you know what, I'm going to give us two weeks to tackle this project
没错，所以你知道吗，我打算给我们两周时间来处理这个项目，
because it's a very difficult one.
因为它非常困难。
Alright, very good.
好的，非常好。
And well actually when he was getting some questions from the audience members specifically
实际上，当他从观众那里收到一些具体问题时，
because he was kind of being interrupted, he was very polite about it and to kind of
因为他有点被打断，他对此非常有礼貌，并且为了
defer the question he said, you know what, that's a fair point but I'll tackle that question
推迟问题，他说：“你知道吗，这是个合理的观点，但我稍后会处理那个问题。”
later on.
稍后。
Okay, and so this is a really great phrase if you want to flatter someone, make them
好的，所以这是一个非常好的短语，如果你想恭维某人，让他们
feel good before you tell them that you're not going to answer their question.
在你说不回答他们的问题之前感觉良好。
Or maybe you disagree with someone so I could say, you know what Marco, chocolate cake is
或者也许你不同意某人，所以我可以这样说：“你知道吗，马可，巧克力蛋糕是
the only cake in the entire world that people should eat.
全世界唯一应该吃的蛋糕。”
Okay, and I could say something like that's a fair point but in my opinion vanilla cake
好的，我可以这样说：“这是个合理的观点，但在我看来，香草蛋糕
is better.
更好。”
Alright, so see what Marco did?
好的，看到马可做了什么吗？
He made me feel good.
他让我感觉很好。
He said, you know, fair point, that's a good idea but I disagree or but in the case of
他说：“你知道吗，合理的观点，这是个好主意，但我不同意”，或者在这个
today's dialogue but we'll talk about that later.
今天的对话中，但我们会稍后讨论。
Right, and actually he did another smart thing in the way that he used his language skills
对，实际上他在这里还做了另一件聪明的事，他运用了自己的语言技巧，
here when he was interrupted again he said, hey, you know what, I'd be happy to answer
当他再次被打断时，他说：“嘿，你知道吗，我很乐意
your questions at a later time or in the Q&A session.
稍后或在问答环节回答你的问题。”
Okay, so this phrase, I'd be happy to.
好的，所以这个短语是“我很乐意”。
I'd be happy to talk about that at a later time but right now I'm trying to explain something
我很乐意稍后讨论那个，但现在我正在解释其他
else.
事情。
Exactly, so these are two really, really key phrases for trying to in a nice way change
没错，所以这是两个非常关键的短语，用于以礼貌的方式改变
the topic or change the conversation.
话题或转换对话。
So yeah, I guess you can say, yeah, I'd be happy to talk about that later on or I'll
所以是的，我想你可以说：“是的，我很乐意稍后讨论那个”或“我
tackle that question in a little bit or that's a fair point but we'll talk about it later
会稍后处理那个问题”或“这是个合理的观点，但我们稍后会讨论它”。
on.
稍后。
Okay, so a lot of great language there.
好的，这里有很多很棒的语言。
Why don't we take a last listen to our dialogue and review everything we've just learned.
我们为什么不最后听一遍我们的对话，回顾一下我们刚刚学到的所有内容。
Now as we've already discussed, there's a huge untapped market out there both in Asia,
正如我们已经讨论过的，在亚洲、
in other developing markets and in the more mature markets for us to push into.
其他发展中市场和更成熟的市场中，有一个巨大的未开发市场等待我们进入。
Now of course this represents an enormous challenge with enormous rewards for the winners
当然，这代表着巨大的挑战，对赢家来说也有巨大的回报，
but for any new product we need a great marketing message and marketing campaign.
但对于任何新产品，我们需要一个强大的营销信息和营销活动。
It needs to be directed and focused at our target consumer and needs to be pitched at
它需要针对我们的目标消费者，并以
exactly the right level.
恰到好处的水平进行宣传。
The question we must first address is of course who is our target consumer and secondly what
我们首先要解决的问题当然是：谁是我们的目标消费者？其次，
do they expect from the next generation alpha laptop?
他们对下一代阿尔法笔记本电脑有什么期望？
Let's first of all tackle the first question.
让我们首先处理第一个问题。
Our target consumer for the X420 is the middle class white collar worker with an above average
我们X420的目标消费者是收入高于平均水平的
income.
中产阶级白领工人。
However, as we mentioned before, the total number of computer owners is expanding rapidly
然而，正如我们之前提到的，电脑拥有者的总数正在迅速增长，
and we need to broaden our audience for this product.
我们需要为这个产品扩大受众。
For example, the X420 is also ideally suited to the younger student sector who might use
例如，X420也非常适合年轻学生群体，他们可能
laptops both for studying and gaming.
既用于学习也用于游戏。
There is no doubt that…
毫无疑问……
Mr. Ford, if I could just interrupt a moment.
福特先生，如果我能打断一下。
You say that the computer is suitable for students but you don't think the price of
你说这款电脑适合学生，但你不认为X420的价格
the X420 is just too much for most students?
对大多数学生来说太高了吗？
Well that's a fair point.
嗯，这是个合理的观点。
If you don't mind, I'd like to tackle your question a little bit later in the Q&A section.
如果你不介意，我想稍后在问答环节处理你的问题。
Is that okay?
可以吗？
Yes, sure.
好的，当然。
Okay, so as I was saying, we have an exciting campaign planned for the X420.
好的，正如我所说，我们为X420计划了一个激动人心的活动。
Firstly we'll have a nationwide television campaign as well as advertising on radio and
首先，我们将有一个全国性的电视广告活动，以及在广播和
also in many computer publications.
许多电脑出版物上的广告。
We also intend to…
我们还打算……
I'm sorry to stop you Mr. Ford, but do you really think that a television campaign is
抱歉打断你，福特先生，但你真的认为电视广告活动
cost effective?
成本效益高吗？
I mean, how much does that go into cost?
我的意思是，这要花多少钱？
Well I don't have the figures to hand, but I'd be happy to discuss those figures with
嗯，我手头没有具体数字，但我很乐意在演示结束后
you after the presentation.
和你讨论这些数字。
Okay let me just go on to talk a little more about the exciting campaign we have in store.
好的，让我继续谈谈我们准备的这个激动人心的活动。
All right, so this was part five of our presentation series.
好了，这是我们演示系列的第五部分。
We're halfway done with it and so far we've seen a lot of interesting things and as you
我们已经完成了一半，到目前为止我们看到很多有趣的内容，正如你
notice it's an intermediate lesson so it is a little bit more challenging and a little
注意到的，这是一个中级课程，所以它比之前的课程
bit longer than your previous lessons.
更具挑战性，也稍长一些。
That's right, these are longer and some of the phrases that you've learned, these words
没错，这些词比较长，而且有些是你学过的短语，这些词
are very difficult.
非常难。
But as a reminder, some of the words repeat.
但提醒一下，有些词会重复出现。
So for example in today's dialogue we heard a lot about developing markets and campaigns,
比如在今天的对话中，我们听到了很多关于开发市场和营销活动的内容，
but we also heard about these last week in episode four.
但上周第四集里也提到了这些。
So if you're confused or you want some extra practice, I would recommend listening to some
所以如果你感到困惑或想额外练习，我建议再听一些
of the older lessons again just to review because you're going to hear a lot of these
之前的课程来复习，因为你会反复听到很多这样的
words and phrases over and over again.
词汇和短语。
That's right and of course if you have any questions about this or any suggestions you
没错，当然如果你对此有任何问题或建议，
can also come to our website EnglishPod.com where we'll see everyone there.
也可以访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，我们会在那里和大家见面。
That's right, so until next week, bye everyone.
没错，那么下周见，大家再见。